This is Chapter 1 of the flask make a tutorial welcome.
Before we begin I want to spend a couple of minutes showing you how you can work.
But the code repository and get hub.
Why'd you do this tutorial.
The address is get hub dot com slash Miguel Greenburgh slash microblog.
And this repository is carefully structured with one commit per chapter.
So if you are doing chapter one as is the case now you can click on the commit and see exactly what
changes went in to that chapter
and other useful option is to click on the browse button on the right for the commit and this will give
you a browse several repository at that chapter.
From here you can also download a zip file if you want to have the files locally on your machine.
The first few chapters are simple enough that I'm going to type them directly and I recommend that you
do too so that you familiarized with the project later on when the code changes become longer and a
little bit more complicated.
You may want to come to this repository to copy and paste certain sections that will be very tedious
to write.