So let's write a first version of microblog flask.
It's a simple enough framework that you can write an entire application in a single file but that is
not what I'm going to do here.
We are going to be growing this application considerably.
So I'm going to start from a better project structure before you begin.
Remember to make your microblog directory your current directory and also to activate the virtual environment.
So the first thing that I'm going to do is I'm going to create a package where the application source
files will live.
My package is going to be called up.
So I create a directory for it in python.
A package is a directory that has a special module that's called in it thought pi.
So now I'm going to create this module
A quick note about editors you should know that you can use any text editor that you like to write your
Python application for this tutorial.
I'm going to use them but that is not a requirement.
If you like more powerful editors are actually ideas such as pi charm or Visual Studio code.
Those are perfectly fine for this tutorial.
So OK I'm going to write the code for the init PI Montral.
So let's go over this code in line 1.
I'm importing a flask class with uppercase F from the flask package.
You'll recall that when we tested a flask was correctly installed in our virtual environment we typed
in port flask.
In this case I'm using a more specialized import where I'm defining exactly what I need to import from
flask instead of importing the entire package in Langtry.
I create an instance of this class flask that I imported and I store it in a variable called app..
The argument that I'm passing to flask is the name variable from Python.
This variable provides the name of the package flask uses this value to find out what's the location
of this package on disk so that it can then locate other files in the same location in 9:5.
I'm importing a route's module also from this package and this module doesn't exist yet.
This is what I'm going to write next.
You may find it odd that there is an import in the bottom line we normally put imports at the top.
In Python This is done intentionally to avoid a common problem with flask which is the problem of circular
dependencies.
You are going to see in a moment when I write the routes module that this module needs to import this
variable.
This creates a mutual dependency between these two modules and if I put this import at the top will
make Python throw errors.
There are a few ways to address similar dependency problems in Python and one of the methods is to move
the offending import on one of the modules to the bottom so that is what I'm doing here so I can save
this and move to the next module which is route's top pie.
So I'm going to open up slash Krauts.
Py.
And this is going to be the module in which I'm going to define the logic of the application.
So I'm going to start with something very simple.
What I want to do is that when I connect this application from a web browser I want to see a Hello World
message displayed in the browser page.
What I can do is I can write a function that returns the text that I want to see in the browser.
I'm going to call it index and it's going to return.
Hello world.
Now I need to tell flask that this is the function that I want to execute when a user connects to the
application from a web browser and flask provides a decorator to do that.
You may not be familiar with decorators.
This is a very cool feature of the Python language that allows you to enhance functions with additional
behavior.
Decorator is written above a function and it starts with the sign they approach decorator from flask
creates a mapping between a u r l and a function.
So here I'm saying that I want to associate the slash r l so that the top level you are l of my application
with this function to make this work I need to import my application which was defined in it.
By now I should note these two apps here that I've seen some people getting confused with.
We have an app package which is this one this is represented on disk by the app directory and we also
have an app variable that I'd find in any top pie here.
So what I'm doing here is I'm importing the app variable defined inside the app package.
I've seen some people that prefer to use the same name for the package and the application instance
and an equal number of people prefer to use different names.
So if you find this confusing it's totally fine if you use a different name for one of these two.
And I would like to suggest that in that case you rename your directory and your package to.
For example my app and then you will have different names so to complete this example I'm going to add
a second.
Well that's also going to be mapped to the same function.
This is perfectly fine you can chain decorators.
And in this case the opera decorator will allow you to assign more than one.
You are able to the same function.
So now we created our first flask route before we can run this example.
We need to add a top level script that represent the application.
So this goes outside of the package in the microblog directory.
I'm going to call the script microblog not pi and the only thing that the script needs to do is import
the applications from the app package.
We import app and this is from where flask is going to obtain our application instance.
It's now complete.
So I can save and exit
and to tell flask where the application is located.
Now I need to define an environment variable called flask up so floss is going to be set to microblog
that pi which is the module that defines the application.
We do not need to get flask the name of the application because by the default flag we look for a variable
called app in this module that we said in this environment variable if you're working on Windows and
you're using the command prompt then to set an environment variable you will use set instead of export
like that.
So keep that in mind.
Now we are ready to run the first version of our application.
So for that I'm going to say a flask run and that started the application server.
Here you see that the command shows me the location of the application.
This is how I'm going to access this application from my web browser.
So what I can do now is copy the while and go to a web browser and paste it and we see here.
We're going to make this a little bit bigger.
So let's review what happened here.
The web browser or receive the URL that I typed in the address bar then it sent a request to this IP
address which is the IP address of your own machine.
This is always the same.
This refers to your own machine and this number.
Web servers run on an IP address an important number.
So these are the ones that the flask server is using.
So the browser has sent the request and since there is no path it's going to request the slash you are
l the top level you are l.
So flask on the server receives the request that want URL is slash.
So it looks at all that you or else it knows about.
And it found a match.
So then it invokes the function that was associated with that.
You know when the function returns flask takes the return value and passes it on back to the client.
That web browser and the web browser then displays it on the page.
So it's pretty simple right.
If you recall I have also said a second you are l associated with the same function.
So that was slash index if I type slash index in the address bar I still get the same response.
But if I type something else.
So for example slash foo then I get an error because flask does not know about Slash.
We didn't write any routes for this.
You are going to go back to my terminal window and here when I need to stop the server I need to press
control-C and that is going to bring you back to your command prompt.
This completes the first version of microblog.
I suggest you familiarize yourself with this project by making changes to this application.
You may want to add more routes to implement different you or else different responses different text.
If you know a little bit of a DML you can write the email in that response.
It doesn't need to be just a string.
You can include a DML elements in it and once you feel comfortable that you have an understanding of
how routes work in flask I think you're ready to move to chapter two.